Preliminary Guide to The Thomas Hahn Chesapeake and Ohio Canal collection, 1939-1993 MS2020
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
The Thomas Hahn Chesapeake and Ohio Canal collection
1939-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Hahn, Thomas F.
MS2020
10 Linear Feet
Collection contains materials related to Thomas Hahn's involvement in the C&O Canal Association, as well as other canals related to the C&O, and canals in general. A large part of the collection consists of photographic negatives, slides and prints of the C&O Canal. Most of these photographs, negatives, and slides relate to illustrations in publications that he authored or co-authored. Other items include reference material for his books, correspondence, and maps.
10 Linear feet (30 boxes)
Box 31
Box 30
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Biographical Note
Thomas Hahn (1926- 2007) was a professional industrial archaeologist, a college professor and a bona fide Indian medicine man. He was born in November 1926, in Topeka, Kansas. After retiring from the Navy following a 28 year career, Hahn earned several degrees including a Masters degree in History and a PhD in Industrial Archeology. He spoke five language and was closely connected with his Native American heritage and at one point in his life served as Chief of the Kansas Delawares Nation.
Hahn had a 28-year career in the Navy that spanned three wars, beginning in 1944 as a seaman second class and ended in retirement in 1972 with a captain's rank. He wrote 30 volumes on the C&O Canal for the National Park Service, as well as historical books, essays and brochures.
He was considered one of the world's foremost expert on the C&O Canal. He was the field archaeologist on two major canal restoration projects; one in Havre de Grace, Md., the other in Alexandria, Va. Hahn founded national and international canal societies as a way of sharing information. He was president and founder of the 25-member Eastern West Virginia Archeology Society and served as president of the American Canal Association from 1972-97.
Collection Scope and Content
This Collection contains materials related to Thomas Hahn's involvement in the C&O Canal Association, as well as other canals related to the C&O, and canals in general.
A large part of the collection consists of photographic negatives, slides and prints of the C&O Canal. Most of these photographs, negatives, and slides relate to illustrations in publications that he authored or co-authored. Other items include reference material for his books, correspondence, and maps.
Please note: many of the images, especially those in boxes 21-25, are not in order and may require additional time to use for research.
The collection covers the years from 1939-1993 and is housed in 31 boxes, or approximately 10 linear feet.
Maps; Color slides; Havre de Grace (Md.); Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Black-and-white slides; Canals; Photographs; Washington (D.C.); Alexandria (Va.); Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association; Hahn, Thomas F.; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park (Agency: U.S.)
- Lock 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lock 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lock 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lock 4, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lock 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lock 6, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lock 7, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lock 8, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lock 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lock 10, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lock 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lock 12, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lock 13, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  General
  This folder is empty
- Lock 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lock 15, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lock 16, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Lock 17, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lock 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lock 19, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Lock 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lock 21, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Lock 22, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Lock 23, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Lock 24, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Lock 25, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Lock 26, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lock 27, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lock 28, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lock 29, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lock 30, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Lock 31, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Lock 32, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lock 33, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Lock 34, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Lock 35, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Lock 36, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Lock 37, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Lock 38, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Lock 39, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Lock 40, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Lock 41, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lock 42, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Lock 43, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Lock 44, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Lock 45, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Lock 46, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lock 47, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lock 48, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lock 49, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Lock 50, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lock 51, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Lock 52, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Lock 54, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lock 55, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Lock 56, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Lock 57, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lock 58, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lock 59, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Lock 60, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Lock 61, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Lock 62, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Lock 63, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Lock 64, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Lock 65, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Lock 66, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Lock 67, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Lock 68, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Lock 69, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Lock 70, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Lock 71, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Lock 72, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Lock 73, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Lock 74, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Lock 75, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 1 No. 1 March, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 1 No. 2 April, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 1 No. 3 May, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 1 No. 4 June, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 1 No. 5 November 5, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 2 No. 1 February 18, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 2 No. 2 April 30, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 2 No. 3 October 19, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 3 No. 1 February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 3 No. 2 May 19, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 4 No. 1 October, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 4 No. 2 January, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- "Along the Towpath": V. 6 No. 2 May, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- "Along the Towpath": Section of the Month; The Georgetown Canal Incline by Harold Skramstad, nd., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- "Along the Towpath": Section of the Month; Paw Paw Tunnel by Alan Franklin, nd., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- "Along the Towpath": Section of the Month, Georgetown Tidal Lock-Old Boat Incline by: Rae T. Lewis, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
- "Along the Towpath": Canal of the Month; The Jams River & Kanawha Canal in Richmond by William E. Trout, nd., undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Along the Towpath, Level Walkers Report on Towpath Conditions, nd., undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Along the Towpath, Level Walker Directory, nd., undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
- "Along the Towpath": Resume of Level Walker & Answers to Questionaire Regarding the Development of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park, nd. Prepared by: Tom Hahn, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- "Along the Towpath": C&O Canal National Historic Park, culverts, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- City map of Washington, DC during the time of the city canal, nd., undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, Distances from the Lock at Georgetown, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Diagram of Georgetown, showing C&O Canal and Riverfront Development, 1830-1900 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- The Chesapeake and Ohio Canal and The Antebellum Commerce of Old Georgetown. By Rogers W. Young -- January, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Georgetown Commerce Prior to, 1830 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Canal in Georgetown area, Tidelock with boat, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Canal in Georgetown area; Godey Lime Kilns on Rock Creek, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Canal in Georgetown area; Lock #3, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Canal in Georgetown area: Lock #4, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Cover of Along the C&O by Dave & Martha Kelsey, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Along the C&O Canal calendar. Picture of Lock #23, Winter, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Along the C&O Canal calendar. Picture of Monocacy Aqueduct, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Along the C&O Canal calendar. Picture of Great Falls during Douglas Reunion Hike, 1974., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Along the C&O Canal calendar. Georgetown, Lock 4, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Along the C&O calendar. Picture of Dam #2, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Approximate length of sections of C&O Canal that will be Narrowed to 27'. April 7, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Photograph by Judge Richard A. Kennedy of John McDaniel's house on the C&O Canal, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Composite Lock Sketch, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Photocopy of map of Maryland and Delaware, by Johnson & Ward.(Shows Civil War & Defenses of Washington), 1860-1870 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Drawing of canal boat at Brunswick, from a calendar, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Xerox copy of Civil War engraving of Aqueduct of the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, at the mouth of the Monocacy, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Construction & Maintenance of the C&O Canal Dam No. 1 Little Falls, MD, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Historical Report Godey Lime Kilns, Washington DC, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Hydrologic capacity of the C&O Canal between Great Falls and Pennyfield Lock, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- To the Presidents & Directors of the C&O Canal. March 5, 1829 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Blueprint of lock, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Document regarding the construction of the towing path along Potomac River, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Documents regarding culverts along the C&O Canal, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Reconstruction work of C&O Canal, 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- US Gov't Memorandum from Superintendent to Chief of Maintenance. June 20, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Report on C&O Canal to February 1, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Specification of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Specifications of a stone bridge, 1829 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Notecards regarding C&O Canal, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Geology and Engineering, Chesapeake and Ohio Canal; Spring Gap to Cumberland by Geraldine H. and William E. Davies, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
- C&O Canal Song: "Canal Saga", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Sketch of Lock #66 and its immediate vicinity, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Records of the Columbia Historical Society of Washington, DC, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- In-service Field Trip, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Unit on the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Stranger's Guide to Washington, DC; The City As Mr. Lincoln Knew it., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- From Tiber Creek to Murder Bay: The Failure of the Washington Canal, nd, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Old Canals Revival in the USA, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Map of Pittsburg and its environs, 1830 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Transcontinental Line; sketch showing the position of the Principal bench -- Marks Sandy Hook, NJ to Parkersburg, W.VA, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous documents, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Interview of Joe Sandblower by Ed Weseley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Interview of Shannon by Ed Weseley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Interview of Mary Schroeder by Ed Weseley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Interview of Mr. Sisler by Ed Weseley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Oral history of Lloyd Shives, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- History of Martin Stevens by Tom Hahn, Nov. 12, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Interview of Clifford Swain by Tom Hahn, Dec., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Recording between Clifford Swain, former boatman on the C&O Canal and Ross Holland, historian, C&O Canal National Monument, nd., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Interview with John L. Swain by Martha Ross, Aug., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Interview of Clifford Swain by Ranger Winehold, Sept., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Interview with Maimie Swain by Martha Ross at Williamsport, MD. Sept. 1, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Interview of Mr. Little of Hancock by Ed Wesley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Interview of Mr. J.P. Mose by Tom Hahn at Hagerstown, MD. Jan 6, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Interview of Mr. J.P. Mose by Tom Hahn. Nov. 16, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Interview with Lavenia Waskey by Martha Ross at Frederick, MD. Sept. 5, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Interview with George W. "Hooper" Wolfe by Ed Wesley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Interview with Mr. Williams by Ed Wesley at C&O CanalHeadquarters, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Interview of Mrs. Rosalie Younker by Martha Ross at Hancock, MD. May 27, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Interview of Frank Zimmerman by Tom Hahn at Hancock, MD. Oct. 3, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Oral interview with Clara Manning. May 26, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Oral interview with Jack Meyers by Ed Wesley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Time Was Interview with 18 Old-Timers by Elizabeth Kytle. May, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Oral Interview with Earl Kronk of Harper's Ferry by Ed Wesley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Interview with Cecil Jamison, age 72, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Interview with Mrs. Joe Higgins by Ed Wesley -- Sons Raymond & Joe, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Interview of Louise Hebb of Sharpsburg, July 7, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Interview of Mr. Haugh of Oldtown, MD by Ed Wesley, nd, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Oral interview with Bill Clipper by Ed Wesley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Interview of Roy Gray and others who worked on the canal in its operating days. Interview conducted by William Clark. July 29, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Interview with Pat Boyer, nd., undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
- C&O Canal HQ Tape #49, Family Reunion Day. Oral History of Tom Bissett. Oct. 27, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Oral interview with Roy (Ray) Bender by Ed Weseley, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Notes from a oral interview of Byron Bender. Sept. 10, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- YACC Interview with Mr. Bansoff. July 10, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Interview with Julius Apple by Martha Ross., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Oral interview with Julius Apple of Berkeley Springs, WV. Interview conducted by Martha Ross. May 26, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Assignment for Psychology 300 taught by Thomas Hahn, nd., undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
- C&O Canal HQ Tape #48 Composite interview of various tapes, nd, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
- YACC Interview with Mr. Brandt of Williamsport. July 17, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Correspondence from Joseph Rodenick to Tom Hahn, nd, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Letter from Henry Richards, August, 1829 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Letter from James Forman of Boating of Flour & C. August 7, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Letter from Charles Fisk to unknown. June 2, 1848 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Letter from Edgar W. Young to Mr. C.H. Cross. September 14, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Letter from Cornelius W. Heine to Dr. John A Muscalus concerning to the C&O Canal. April 25, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Letter from William Johnson to Tom Hahn. May 3, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Letter from Charles Mathias, J. Glenn Beall, Jr. Gilbert Gude to Mr. George Hartzog. October 6, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Letter from Lavenia Waskey to Thomas Hahn. November, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Letter from Lorenia Waskey to Tom Hahn. January 11, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Letter from Clifford C. Swain to Tom Hahn regarding the C&O near Hagerstown, MD. April 21, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Correspondence from Joseph Prentice. United States Department of the Interior to Superintendent of C&O Canal. July 3, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Letter from Joseph R. Prentice of the United States Department of the Interior to Superintendent of the C&O Canal. July 17, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Correspondence to Mr. Roger W. Squires dated September 23, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Letter from John M Lamb to "Carroll" March 10, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Letter from William E. Trout III to Willard H. Duetting June 6, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Letter from Lucia J. Dunham to Thomas F. Hahn. September 24, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Letter from Donald Ray Barnes to Thomas F. Hahn November 6, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Three letters from "Sam" to Thomas F. Hahn, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Letter from L.S. Baier to Thomas F. Hahn February 16, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Letter from Jim Wilson of the Steamship Historical Society Of America to Thomas F. Hahn. March 28, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Correspondence between Mrs. Vera Saunders and Thomas Hahn. October 1 & October 18, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Letter from Jean Libby to Thomas F. Hahn. August 12, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- 3 Letters from Lester Rackey to Thomas F. Hahn, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Letter from Geo. W. Hooper Wolfe to Thomas F. Hahn. March 17, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Letter from Charles L. Shoup to Thomas F. Hahn. April 2, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Correspondence from Lester Racker to Thomas F. Hahn, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Letter from Lester Racky to Thomas F. Hahn October 16, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Letter from Emily to Thomas F. Hahn October 31, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Letter to Thomas F. Hahn from Chalmers M. Roberts September 26, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Two correspondences from Frederic Gutheim to Thomas F. Hahn. February, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Letter from Mrs. Lee H. Hough to Thomas F. Hahn April, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Correspondence from Mrs. Lillian Langdon to Thomas F Hahn regarding C&O Canal. July 25, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Letters from Emily to Thomas F Hahn regarding canal prints., 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Letter from Lester to Thomas F Hahn. February 17, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Letter from Maxine P. Hanberry to Thomas F Hahn July 14, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Letter from Richard Stanton to Thomas F Hahn August 13, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Letter from MV Batten to Thomas F Hahn November 19, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Correspondence between Thomas F Hahn and Elizabeth Kytle regarding Thomas F Hahn's book., 1986 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Letter from Lester to Thomas F Hahn. June, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Letter from William J. Bray, Jr. to the American Canal July 17, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Correspondence from W. Edward News to Thomas F Hahn regarding Lock #70. May 9, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Letter from W.E. Trout III. November 2, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Letter from Bruce Peeling to Thomas F Hahn January 11, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Letter from Mary to Joe. August 31, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Letters from Lester to Thomas F Hahn included are pictures of the canal in Georgetown, nd, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous letters to Thomas F Hahn, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Letter from Mrs. Davis V Frozier to Thomas F Hahn. April 3, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Correspondence with Samuel Davis & family, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Orville Crowder's Notes on the C&O Canal, donated by Thomas Hahn. Sections 1-8, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Orville Crowder's Notes on the C&O Canal, donated by Thomas Hahn. Sections 9-15, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service Historic Structures Report Part 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- History and Legislation of C&O Canal, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Courtcase: Francis Cooper vs. C&O Canal Co. Jan 18, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- C&O Canal Flood, nd., undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- New York State Department of Transportation. Barge Canal System & Connecting Waterways, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Various landscape postcards of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Narrative of C&O Canal and Boatman, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Manuscript of the book, "The Log of the good Ship Joruva". A Tale of the Towpath by R.E. Wagstaff, W.D. McNair, W.S. Dotwiler, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Georgetown Outlet Incline, nd., undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- The Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, nd., undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- C&O Canal Seal & Medal, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- C&O Canal By-Laws, Rules, and Regulations. April 1, 1851 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- General Laws 51st Council, 1853 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- General Summary of C&O Canal, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- C&O Canal, Great Falls, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- C&O Canal Lock Schematic, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Blueprint of C&O Canal Company Steam Yacht "Maryland", undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Blue prints of Typical Canal Freight Barge, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Boats & Barges of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Blue prints of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Blue prints of a canal boat on the C&O, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Blue prints of a canal boat on the C&O, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Blue prints of a C&O Canal Barge. Dated Feb. 22, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- C&O Canal Restoration Project, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
- C&O Canal Lock-Keepers and Boatmen, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
- C&O Canal list of officers and rates of toll. April 1, 1851 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Violett's Lock, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Dam #2, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Former maintenance employees of receivers of C&O Canal Company taken over by the National Capital Parks Effective Nov. 1, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- 1979 Hike Reunion Song, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
- C&O Canal, National Historic Park. Great Falls, MD. Development Concept Plan, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Hiker's Guide to the C&O Canal. Compiled by Grant Conway. April 27, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Blueprints of the C&O Canal Projects, nd, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Canals and the Navigable Riveres of the Canada, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- State of New York, Dept. of Public Works. Official map, Showing barge canal system and connecting waterways., undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
- The Hutton Papers, nd., undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Uleuerton, nd, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "Coal From Cumberland", Scharf, 1435, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- "The Discovery of Gold at Great Falls, MD 1861" by Edgar T. Ingalls, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Potomac River Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- The Chesapeake and Ohio Canal: It's Relationship to the Civil War by Dr. Richard Mertz, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Duvall Foundry, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
- C&O Canal Seal, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Supreme Court of the United States Letters from Justice William Douglas. February 5, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Documenting the Lock Gates and Structure at Lock 14 of the Illinois and Michigan Canal., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- "The Life and Work of Women on the C&O Canal" by Mayris Fitzsimons, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
- A list of culverts along the C&O Canal, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Harlen Innau's introduction of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Characterestics of the Boatmen: 1891-1924 by Harlen Innau, nd, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Guide to the Geology and Engineering of the C&O Canal Seneca to Carderock, nd, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
- C&O Canal, Ft. Frederick to Williamsport Guide to the Engineering and Geology by G.H & W.E Davies, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
- The Toll Chart of1857 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Tickets for one adult for the Canal Clipper on the C&O Canal., undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Report on the Potomac River and its tributaries., undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Condensed Mileage Chart, C&O Canal Towpath, October - December, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 20)